Alright, so we are on the last part of sales here.
We have gone through the entire
process a number of times now.
We've gone through the analysis,
which is the big meaty part of this.
We've talked about the proposal
and the scope of work on the last call,
the proposal call is something that you can do, right?
So if we go back again to our process,
it is the discovery call.
Number one, after discovery call, we qualify them
and say, yes, you are qualified.
Yes, we've asked you about your budget
or your expectations of pricing
and it it matches with what we would present to you.
'cause you pretty should know that off the top of your head.
Basically at this point, you do the analysis,
you gotta have an analysis call with them.
That analysis call sometimes can be
the, the deal be made there.
After that you go through the analysis is the scope of work,
the proposal, which is the word document
that we went through last time.
Depending on the prospect, you might want to have a,
a follow up call to go through line item by line item.
What's inside of that proposal and scope of work.
I would say we do it about 50% of the time.
Some clients after going
through the analysis call feel like they have everything
that they need and they're like, just send me
the proposal and we'll take a look.
You know, I do like to have a a, a proposal call
because to me the more,
the more conversations you can have, the better.
Because it removes questions, it gives more clarity.
And just the more touch points, quite frankly is, is more
of a chance to really showcase yourself
and build a relationship with that prospect.
I have one, yes, I had an analysis call yesterday
where it went for like an hour and 20 minutes.
It went way over. We didn't even get to go through the scope
of work 'cause there were so many questions on the analysis.
So I made sure on that call to book a follow up,
to review the proposal next week
because I do wanna make you do wanna make sure that you go
through these service offerings.
'cause that document that I sent you,
if you don't have a chance to kind of touch base
with it on the analysis call, it's,
there's a lot of information in there.
There's a lot of deliverables in there.
They might not know what they are, so they might not
understand and see the value in it.
So the proposal call is something where you,
you wanna make sure that you're having that.
Now also on the proposal call too, this is, if you get that,
this is your chance to close, right?
So there's language that you can use on closing calls
or closing sequences that now's the time
where you can put on like your wolf
of Wall Street hat a little bit.
Where up until now you've been a consultant.
Now it's time where there's a level of accountability
on their part right now
because they have put you through a couple of calls,
they've put you through analysis that they've requested.
You both have skin in the game now
where you can start making a very, I don't say aggressive,
but very cognizant and very intentional about closing.
So on the proposal call, especially
if you can get them on a proposal call, this is
where you wanna start going after more of the hard close.
So language that you'd want to use on that would be,
you know, do you understand everything
that you're getting when you're getting it?
Talk to me about, tell me where you're at.
I usually like to use, use kind
of like open-ended language like that.
Like tell me where you're at. Where does this land?
Is this, does this meet your expectations?
This, do you feel like this proposal
that we put forth can help us meet the goals
that we talked about on your discovery
Call in terms of your lead generation?
You know, a lot of times they're gonna say yes, right?
Which is good. You're kind of like walking them into it.
A lot of times people are gonna be like, no.
At that point, if they are, then you say, well,
where do we miss and how can we adjust this to,
to make sure this is also a really good chance
to have the honest conversation about pricing, right?
Because what you don't wanna do is walk away from that call.
We wanna make sure that we're not letting them go without
having a discussion about the pricing on,
I'll ask them directly say, how does this, is this pricing?
This is what I had told you, is this, is this in alignment
with what you were expecting?
Is this, is this something that you're comfortable with?
Right? You wanna have that conversation.
'cause we don't wanna, we don't wanna let them walk away
because this is when ghosting starts to happen,
when there's mis met expectations when they don't really
maybe have the courage to tell you that.
Like, it's just too expensive.
You know, sometimes people will,
but it's good to just communicate about this stuff
and just have honest and direct conversations about it.
And then, you know, language that I also like
to use too is, are you ready?
Like, when, when would be a good start date for you?
I like to make the assumption
that they're gonna go with it, right?
Because if you get to this point, then I, that's kind
of my way of saying, are you in, so I'll say
when would be a good start date for you?
Right? I won't, I I won't even ask like, are you in,
I'll just say, when would be a good start date for you?
We can get you started as soon as next Monday.
How does that look for you? And they'll be like, oh,
you know, we have to think about it.
We gotta talk about it. Okay, that's not a problem.
When can I expect a decision from you?
It's really, really, really important
that you use that language.
It's really, really important that you ask that question
because what we're doing is we're setting accountability
for follow ups, right?
So now we're starting to get into the follow up
and close part of this process where it's really just about
asking a few of the right questions.
When would be a good time for you to start?
Yeah, we can do Monday. Great.
We'll let's talk about next steps. We'll talk what that is.
Now we're, we need a little bit more time,
we gotta talk to our CEO.
Okay, great. When can I expect an
ex decision from you on this?
And they should give you a date.
And if they don't, then you need to push back
and be like, hey, hey, you know,
like we're, we're very busy.
We need to make sure that we're planning this stuff out.
You know, we did quite a bit of work to get this to you.
Why don't we say, if you need some time,
why don't we say a week from today, no, I need,
okay, how about two weeks from today?
Just keep pushing, right? You need to get a date set
and time because
after you get that date, right,
if they say yes, awesome, you're done.
You just tell them, Hey, we're gonna send over an invoice
to get started, an onboarding email.
Then you go back to the beginning, you
blueprint to find out how to do that.
And it, when they give you a date,
now it gives you something to follow up on, right?
If you're just sending follow
ups being like, Hey, what'd you think?
Hey, what'd you think? Hey, what'd you think?
It's, it's just, it's, it's, it's not a very,
it's not a very, it's not a very good question to ask
because it's very open-ended.
We want to say, Hey Steve,
and I'm gonna show you this in a second,
but like, Hey Steve, you know, you told me
that you'd have a decision in two weeks.
It's been two weeks. How are y'all doing? Where are you at?
Then you can follow up every single day, every single hour.
You can call 'em, you can text 'em
because they told you they put you
through all this work, number one, right?
So there's a level of accountability.
And then number two, they gave you a date
that they would have an expected decision about.
So if they're ghosting you, then you can be very,
very, very, very aggressive.
And this is again, where the
wolf Wall Street comes into play.
So the follow up sequences now call, you know, again,
just going through line by line what's included in the scope
of work when they can expect it in the pricing.
Those, those, it's, it's what, when, how much, right?
Those are the three things that that document answers.
Answer any questions that they have.
And then, like I said, make sure
that you're getting a date or an answer.
This, the, the, the goal here is to get an answer on this.
So again, just to go back
to those questions, when can you get started?
We can get started as soon as next Monday.
How does that sound to you? Number one, they say yes,
say awesome, you know, you're gonna get,
you're gonna get an email from our finance team.
Where should we send the invoice? Get that on the call.
They'll tell you if they say no,
we're not ready, we need time.
Okay, not a problem. Totally understand.
This is a big decision. How much time do you need?
When can I expect the decision from you? I don't know.
I gotta talk to our CEO.
We, we gotta see what's going on with the other agency.
Okay, cool. No problem. I, I understand that, you know,
I understand that this is, again, this is a big decision.
You know, we're, we're, we're proposing quite a big scope
of work here, but we get pretty backed up with work
and we need to make sure that we're planning stuff out on
our end because we don't like
to start more than one client per week.
And if we, that's
so we can give our clients the best service.
So you say you need time, how's one week,
two weeks next month, right?
You have to have to have to get a date, you have
to make sure to set a date.
That's very, very important. So
after that, again, then you can follow up
aggressively on the agreed date.
Date and you can keep following up off of that, right?
You know, I email is just very easy to ignore.
You can, you can start with email again,
just following up on it.
But just call 'em, just pick up the
phone and call or text 'em.
It breaks through, you know, send a voice note.
Just call em, you know, pick up the phone,
call 'em in the middle of the workday
and say, Hey Steve, that's Ryan here.
You told me that you'd have a decision by last week.
I haven't heard back from you. It
feels kinda like you're ghosting me.
You know? Have you been able to,
to put some thought into it, you know?
And look, ghosting is gonna happen. It's extremely annoying.
It's extremely unprofessional.
It makes me want to kick people's teeth in
down the back of their throat.
There's nothing that bothers me more than that.
It's, to me, it's like the ultimate sign of disrespect.
But no matter what, be kind, no matter
how frustrating the prospect is,
I actually had to deal with this the other day.
Went through, I, this is criminal defense
firm that we're pitching in New Jersey.
We're pitching like months ago.
Dude, when I tell you they put us through the ringer
with calls and analysis
and like they were, they were asking for us
to do stuff like, oh, can you look at our YouTube channel?
Like, oh, we just had the agency re our rebuild our website.
Can you do another audit? After we audited
already and we did all of it.
And I was following up for the proposal call nonstop
or a decision and they just ghosted me for like three months
and I was emailing 'em like once a week gone,
holidays came, I was like, you know what?
Forget it. Sent out a, a,
a mass email the other day about chat, GPT ads.
And they responded and they were like, oh yeah,
like, we're interested.
And like when I tell you I was like,
like typing this email back that was like,
you disrespected me to my core.
You asked me and my team for 15 hours of work,
multiple proposals and now you're interested.
And like, I wrote all this stuff out
and I was like, keep working with
that J like I was going off
and then I took a deep, I deleted it
and I just decided I'm just gonna go.
It's always, always better to take the high road if you want
to type it out, make you feel better,
but you kind of have to ask yourself like,
it's gonna feel good in the moment sending this,
but nothing good comes from this.
Like, nothing good comes from it. It's bad for the brand.
They're always gonna blame you.
Like no matter how, like for whatever reason, I don't know,
we work with attorneys, they lack accountability
to their core when it comes to this type of stuff.
And they will, they will go ask you
for all this work and waste all your time.
Even though if people did it to them,
they would feel the exact same way.
The exact same way. Sorry,
I'm getting afraid you can feel my frustration bubbling up.
This obviously happens, but it's just important
that you just take a deep breath
and say, what is the optimal outcome of me sent?
Like, do, do I think he's gonna be
like, oh my God, you're right.
I'm so sorry. Take my money.
No, he is gonna be like telling people that you,
that you're an a-hole.
When I see your ads, I'm gonna
comment that you're an a-hole.
I had one guy go, I did this before he went
and left a negative review on our Google business profile.
So like the point is, is that like it never comes
out like the way you think it does.
They're never gonna be like, oh wow Ryan, you're so right.
You were so gracious to us, we were so wrong. Like, no.
So after that, after they say yes, you know,
we basically just will send over the exact scope of work
that you guys have the proposal,
just have 'em initial it just so they're signing off on it.
We don't do contracts, there's no contract in it,
but y'all do contracts,
make sure you're getting something signed,
something in writing and signed.
And uh, this says stay went from month to month.
I don't know why it says this in here.
This, this is pretty old. We go month to month.
Let's just talk about this for a second actually.
Because a lot of people don't go month to month
or they do do contracts.
I'll, I'll, I'll tell you why I guess
I pivoted away from this.
So we used to always do 12 month contracts.
Cesar, our director of operations always
wants me to do contracts.
If you wanna sell your business,
it's good to have contracts.
I don't do contracts anymore for a couple of reasons.
One, because they don't really matter for retaining clients.
What I mean by that is that if you do a good job,
they're gonna stay and it's much easier
to sell a month to month contract.
And that's really kind of the crux of it too, is
that selling a month to month contract, I tell people,
you know, we're here to make you money if we don't make you
money that we don't deserve to make money.
Whenever I send that line to people,
they're like, oh, I love that.
And I'm like, yeah, so let's go. You know, there's no risk.
I'm able to get people I know for a fact
that if I can get people into, in working with our team,
they're gonna be happy, right?
So me locking them into a long-term contract,
it almost feels unnecessary.
It slows me down a lot when it comes to sales.
So I know that most, pretty much all of our competitors do,
pretty much all of you probably do.
It's totally up to you whether you, whether you do it
or not, but I'm just a firm believer in doing good work.
I know it's crazy, right? Like I
believe in doing good work for people.
I don't believe in forcing people with their,
to like put both their hands behind their back
and get on their knees just to, to
to have some marketing what they've done.
I believe in doing good work, providing good service
and getting results for people, making people money.
So, you know, that's just what I believe.
And our churn rate is almost non-existent on SEO clients.
It's pretty crazy. They don't sign a contract,
but they'll stay with us for years.
So you don't need them to retain long term.
They're gonna stick with you just
based on the work that you do.
So this is, uh, you know,
take it either way I guess if you want,
you know, they're both true.
Both things can be true, but we do not do contracts anymore
and it's really helped to accelerate pushing people over the
finish line because I'm able to then be like, dude, come on.
Like if you don't like me, you
don't even need to gimme 30 days.
Just you can email me
the day before and be like, yeah, we're out.
And I'll be like, okay, that's fine.
And that gets people over the finish line much better,
you know, so just sending a voice
and close and that's really it.
And then I like to do an internal announcement.
This is actually pretty old, this is, Caleb used to work
with us a couple years ago, but you gotta tell the people
internally what is coming down the pipeline.
Who's gonna be working on the campaign.
So inside the team channel, whenever we have a new client,
we'll just do a quick announcement.
Hey, new client signed, this is
who they are, this is their website.
This is what they do, this is the
scope, this is when they start.
Here's some like the, the analysis that we did for 'em.
So you can get familiar with it. We'll talk about it on the
upcoming team call on Monday.
So I'll do the announcement.
It's kind of good to just get some energy flowing, you know,
it's positivity whenever you sign on a new client, people,
you get excited about it and then
I'll bring 'em onto the team call.
So that's it for the slides. Let's get into the questions.
I.